听着 我知道你很累
Look, I know you'r tired.
但想想明早起床时我们就用上新的壁纸了
But just think how good you're gonna feel tomorrow
那感觉会是多么美妙
when you wake up and we have all new shop paper.
我希望自己不懂你说的那种感觉
I wish I didn't get what you are talking about.
但我懂 我真的深有体会
But I do. I just do.
谁会这么晚打电话来
Hey, who could be calling at this hour?
是萨尔
It's Sal.
不 不接了
No. Not answering that.
不管她在经历什么惊天动地的事都可以先等着
Whatever earth-shattering drama she's going through can wait.
除非她找上门来
Until she gets here.
天呐 但愿我们有伏特加
Oh, God. I hope we have vodka.
没有了 米奇尔
We don't, Mitchell.
萨尔是我们年少轻狂的岁月里
Sal was our best girlfriend
最要好的女性朋友
from back in our party days,
但这几年来 我们走上了不同的路
but over the years, we've kind of gone in different directions.
我们选择了向前走
We chose forward.
为什么打不开
Why won't this open?
你们家的门坏了哦
Uh, something's wrong with that door.
好了 无所谓 我有个超棒的消息
Okay, whatever. I have the most amazing news,
我现在超激动
and I'm super excited,
但你们要是不喜欢 我就不激动
but I won't be if you don't want me to be.
准备好了吗
Ready?
我要结婚了
I'm getting married!
天啊 恭喜你
Oh, my gosh! Congratulations!
-我知道 -谁那么幸运
- I know! - Who's the guy?
我的一生挚爱
Oh, the love of my life.
这么说你终于"俘获"了你的老板吗
Oh, so you finally bagged your boss?
对 但不是那个 我没在那里上班了
Oh! Yes, but it's not him. And I don't work there anymore.
他的名字叫托尼
His name is Tony.
我三个月前和他认识的
I met him three months ago.
他是有史以来最棒的男人
He's the greatest guy ever.
说真的 你俩能接受吗
And seriously, are you guys okay with this?
当然 为什么不能呢
Of course. Why wouldn't we be?
因为我能结婚
Well, you know, because I can get married,
但你们俩 不行
and you guys... Ugh! can't.
那又如何 那不意味着你不该结婚
So? That doesn't mean you shouldn't.
真的吗 因为如果你们俩不同意
Really? Because I will not go through with it
我就不结婚 说真的
if you don't want me to. Seriously.
没必要 我们要是剥夺你
Not necessary. I mean, what kind of people would we be
或任何人结婚的权利 那成什么人了
if we denied you or anyone the right to marry?
政客
#politics.
这太让我高兴了
This makes me so happy
因为我想让你们做我的伴郎
because I want you two to be my best men.
-好啊好啊 -当然好了
- Yes! Yes! - Of course!
婚礼会非常小巧可爱
Okay. The wedding is gonna be super cute,
只有我们几个 随后是小型晚宴
Just us, a little dinner after.
就在下周五
Oh, and it's next Friday.
什么 下周五
Oh. What, it's next Friday?
-对 -那我们哪有时间准备伴郎事宜
- Yeah. - How will we have time to do best man stuff?
比如帮你挑选礼服啊
You know, like help you pick out your dress,
准备捧花啊 做做头发啊
get your flowers, get our hair blown out?
他没当过伴郎
He's never been a best man before.
天呐 就要结婚了
Oh, my God, we're getting married!
就要结婚了 来喝一杯吧
We're getting married! Let's have a drink.
-我们没有伏特加了 -我们周五见
- Yeah, we're out of vodka. - I will see you on Friday.
把姓名首字母签在这里 这里和这里
And initial here and here and here.
我的胳膊都酸了
Ay, my arm is starting to hurt.
-就剩几个了 -怎么了
- Just a couple more. - What's going on?
没事 我在收包裹
Nothing. I have to get this package,
要签好多字啊
but there's so much signing.
滚出去 你个变态
Get out of here, you perv.
你怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
你不该在陌生人面前喂奶
You don't do that in front of strangers.
至少要盖个毯子
At least throw a blanket over.
-我并不为此感到羞耻 -显然如此
- I am not ashamed. - Obviously.
你简直毫不吝惜展示她们
They're out all the time--
在曼尼面前 在俱乐部里
in front of Manny, at the club,
前几天在克莱尔的晚宴上
at Claire's dinner the other day.
菲尔差点生吞了支蜡烛
Phil almost ate a candle.
好吧 下次我去小黑衣柜里喂你儿子
Fine. Next time, I will feed your baby inside a dark closet.
我只是希望你喂奶时注意场合
I'm just saying pick your moments, huh?
比如让达丽娅来开门 不然我们雇她干嘛
Like let Daliya open the door. That's why we hired her.
达丽娅
Daliya?
我妈妈养了6个孩子
My mother raised six children
同时还要在建筑工地工作
while working at a construction job.
她会因为我用保姆而感到羞耻的
She would be so ashamed if I had a nanny.
她每个月拿着我的支票取现时
I don't see a lot of shame from your mom
可没觉得她有羞耻心
when she's cashing my checks every month.
达丽娅 我们要去见曼尼的老师
Hey, Daliya, we gotta go see Manny's teacher.
你能来给小家伙拍拍隔吗
Would you try to coax a burp out of this one?
来吧 小家伙
Come here, little guy.
你能把他抱高点吗
Can you hold him a little higher?
我会的 我只是调整下姿势
I will. I'm just letting him get settled in.
好了 我们要走了 再见 乔
Okay, we're going. Bye-bye, Joe.
他喜欢被轻轻地摇晃
He likes to bounce a little.
手稍微弯曲一点
Can you cup your hand
-这样他才不会觉得你在打他 -好的
- so that he doesn't feel like you're slapping? - Okay.
她懂啦 别什么事儿都要管
She knows it. Stop micromanaging.
你手弯曲一点
Cup your hand.
-大家好啊 -好
- Hello. - Hey.
你们今晚谁能载我去参加大提琴演出
Hey, can one of you guys drive me to my cello thing tonight?
宝贝 我们要是早点知道就好了
Honey, I wish we'd known.
是啊 我们得去跟"弗林德森"一家吃晚饭
Yeah. We got a dinner thing with the Flendersons.
你们不用留下来看演出的
Okay, you don't have to stay,
根本没人叫那名字
and those aren't even real people.
抱歉 我刚才慌了
Sorry. I panicked.
在"弗"莱明斯和亨"德森"之间纠结来着
I got stuck between the Flemings and the Hendersons.
天呐 那是新买的靴子吗
Oh, my god. Are those new boots?
是啊
Yes.
我好喜欢 太好看了
I love them. They're so cute!
是吗
They are?
忘了跟你说了
Oh, I forgot to tell you--
丹妮尔·冈斯顿是我们班第一个怀孕的
Danielle Gunston--first one in my class to get pregnant.
完全被你猜中了
You totally called it.
你听到了吗
Did you hear that?
我猜的是丹妮斯·莫迪克
My money was on Denise Modick.
不是 她先是称赞了我的时尚品味
No. First she complimented my fashion sense,
而后又说我做了件对的事儿
then she told me I did something right.
菲尔 我觉得时候到了
Phil, I think it's happening.
养孩子就如同把火箭送上月球
Raising a kid is like sending a rocket ship to the moon.
刚开始几年你们形影不离
You spend the early years in constant contact,
然后忽然间 大概在青春期时
and then one day, around the teenage years,
他们升入黑暗的外太空 消失不见
they go around the dark side and they're gone.
你能做的就是等待一个微弱的信号
All you can do is wait for that faint signal
说他们要回来了
that says they're coming back.
我觉得海莉是在给我发送信号了
I think Haley is sending me that signal.
还有呢
And?
-这个比喻是菲尔想到的 -没错
- And Phil gave me that analogy. - Yeah.
你知道吗
You know what?
我想约她今晚一起出去吃饭
I think I'm gonna ask her out to dinner tonight.
你觉得她会答应吗
Do you think she'll say yes?
你需要的话
If you want,
我可以帮你在自习室给她传个纸条
I can pass her a note in study hall.
我做错什么了
What did I do?
天呐 没什么
Oh, my god. Nothing.
我就是想知道 要是你不忙的话
I just wanted to know, if you weren't busy,
今天晚上 你想不想跟我一起吃饭呢
you know, if you wanted to have dinner with me tonight?
吃饭 就你和我吗
Dinner? Just you and me?
你不是非去不可 没事 算了
I mean, you don't have to. It's cool. Don't worry.
听起来不错 我愿意
No, sounds fun. Let's do it.
好的 那我们到时在前门见咯
Okay. Let's meet by the front door, then.
7点钟怎么样
You know, 7:00?
-好的 -好
- Okay. - Yeah.
我真觉得她喜欢你
I totally think she likes you!
我也这么觉得
I think so, too.
首先我要说美术班能有曼尼这样的学生
First of all, I just want to say what a pleasure it is
真是太荣幸了
to have Manny in art class.
他很有才华
He's talented--
我们直接说他做错什么事了好吗
Can we just skip to what he did wrong?
谁说他做错事了
Who said that he did something wrong?
直说吧
Hit it.
确实有个问题
We do have an issue.
-我就说嘛 -曼尼似乎非常迷恋
- Told you. -Manny seems to have quite a fascination
女性的裸体
with the female nude.
那又怎样 他生性浪漫
So? He's a romantic.
这些是他最近几周的全部画作
Well, this is all his art work over the last few weeks.
我的天
Holy moly.
其实还有更多
There were even more,
不过门卫好像偷了几张回家
but I think the janitor took some home.
看这个
Look at this.
还有这个
And this.
And these.
我是个艺术家 我思想开放
Look, I'm an artist. I'm free.
我曾经在这上面打过耳洞
I used to have an earring up here.
不过有些其他孩子的家长投诉了
But some of the other parents have complained.
都是当妈妈的
Well, the moms.
他一定是在学校学到那些东西的
He must have learned that at school.
因为我们家的电脑装了过滤设备
Because we have filters in the computer,
而且杰的黄色杂志都已经被我扔掉了
and I have thrown out all of Jay magazines.
我不知道她在说什么
Don't know what she's talking about.
曼尼绝对不可能在我们家看到这些东西
There is no way that Manny has seen this sort of thing at our home.
我们会处理的
We'll take it from here.
你好 伙计
Hey, buddy.
今晚就我们父子俩在家
It's just you and me tonight.
听起来不错 我马上下去
Sounds good. I'll be right down.
好的
All right.
我就知道 你藏什么呢
I knew it! What are you hiding?
-黄片儿 -别对我说谎
- Porn. - Don't lie to me!
好吧
Fine.
我正要在Facebook上给一个女孩发信息
I'm trying to send a message to a girl on Facebook,
但她是我高攀不上的女神
but she's so out of my league.
看看她
Look at her.
没错 她很漂亮
Oh, yeah. She's cute.
我都坐在这里好久了
I've been sitting here forever
-就是想不出该说什么 -你可走运了
- and I can't think of anything to say. - Well, you are in luck.
要说有谁知道如何追求女性的话
If anyone knows the art of wooing the fairer sex,
那就是在下了
it's this guy.
"你好"
"Hey."
-等等 -发送
- Wait! - Send.
你怎么可以那么写呢
Why did you type that?
现在她知道我在想她了
Now she knows I'm thinking about her.
笑脸
Smiley face.
我的神呐 快停手吧
Oh, my god. Stop now.
我们这样只会搞砸的
We can only screw it up from here.
拜托 你现在有幸得到大师的指点
Please. You're in the hands of the master.
我觉得我还是知道怎样泡14岁少女的
I think I know how to pick up a 14-year-old girl...
帮你泡
for you.
"今夜漫漫 如何消遣"
"What's the haps tonight?"
走你
Boop.
"今夜漫漫 如何消遣" 没人会这么说的
"What's the haps tonight"? Nobody says that.
"打算逛商场 想见面吗"
"Going to the mall. Wanna meet?"
"一小时后在罗莎烧烤店吃饭如何"
"Dinner at Rosa Grill in an hour?"
问号 发射
Question mark. Boom!
小孩是不吃饭的
Kids don't eat dinner.
不吃饭 你什么意思
What do you mean, you don't eat dinner?
那你们干什么
What do you do?
不知道 就是到处走走 上蹿下跳的
I don't know. You just walk around and jump off stuff.
你不能邀请女孩一起上蹿下跳的
You can't invite a girl to jump off stuff.
可是那总好过...
Well, it's way better than--
"一会儿见 抱抱"
"See ya then. X.O."
妥妥的 伙计
You're in, buddy.
我得准备一下
I gotta get ready.
好了 我们在香味消失前赶紧出发吧
All right, let's go before this wears off.
我觉得那要好几天的时间
I think we have a few days.
谢谢你 酒窝男
Well, thank you, dimples.
你最好别再处处调情了
Oh, you better get that out of your system,
因为再过两小时 你就要成为
'cause in two hours, you're gonna be...
安东尼·伦巴杜太太了
Mrs. Anthony Lombardo.
你那个意大利未婚夫会做饭吗
So does this Italian of yours cook?
在家里每一个房间都"做"
In every room of the house,
你们明白我的意思吧
if you know what I mean!
-我们疯狂做爱 -明白了
- We have a lot of sex. - Yeah. Got it.
好了 现在让我们正正经经地祝酒吧
Okay, now let's have a proper toast. All right.
敬狂野的萨尔
To wild Sal.
你有着惊险刺激的人生经历
You gave it a good run,
但就像每一位传奇的火枪手那样
but like every legendary gunslinger,
终究还是会有刀枪入库
there comes a time when you need to holster your weapons
马放南山的一天
and ride off into the sunset.
但每个来到镇上的男人都被你搞定了
But you took on every man who came to town.
-我确实如此 -必须的
- I really did! - You sure did.
而且 我只是要结婚了而已
Also, you know, I'm just getting married.
又不是要死
I'm not dying.
没有 我们只是为你幸福而感到高兴
No, no. We're just happy you're happy.
而且我们很高兴今后
And we're excited that we're gonna get to see
能更多地跟你见面了
so much more of you now.
是的 我们两对夫妇会成为朋友的
Yes. We'll be couple friends.
我们可以一起去看电影 上课
We'll go to movies... take classes...
还有我们每周六的游戏之夜
Oh, our game nights on Saturday...
-超盛大 -史诗级的
- Huge. - They're epic, yeah.
你玩克雷涅姆桌游吗
Do you play Cranium?
要是我会在周六晚上玩桌游的话
Well, if I'm playing board games on a Saturday night,
你就直接往我头颅上开一枪吧
you can shoot me in my cranium.
不过我还是爱你的
But I love you!
我得去嘘嘘了
I need to take a whiz.
我真为她高兴
I'm so happy for her.
不过我觉得我们可能吓到她了
I think we might have freaked her out, though.
哪有 米奇尔 你是个聪明人
Oh, no, Mitchell. Come on. You're a smart man,
可你不擅长读懂人心
but you are awful at reading people.
萨尔这周大不一样了
Sal's been different this week.
那就是恋爱中的女人
That is a woman in love.
真是个恋爱中的女人啊
Looks like a woman in love.
听着 你喜欢女人 没人比我更高兴
Look, nobody's as happy as I am about you loving the ladies.
我想说的是 你得收敛一点
All I'm saying is, you gotta pull back a little.
-好吧 -曼尼
- Okay. - Ay, Manny,
都怪我
this is all my fault.
我太随心所欲地展现自己的身体了
I am too free with my body.
你小时候这样不要紧 但...
It was okay when you were a little boy, but...
是吗
Was it?
可你现在是个小伙子了
But now that you're a young man,
-而且 -我一个字也没听进去
- and... - I didn't hear a word they said.
我脑子里想的都是达丽娅
All I could think about was Daliya.
每幅画 每首诗
Every drawing, every poem,
每一部历史小说 我都是为她而作
every historical novel I wrote was for her.
她是我的女神
She was my muse.
今生附在那性感的躯体之中
Toss in a body that doesn't quit,
来作我的灵魂伴侣
and I think we got a soul mate.
你可以画别的好多东西啊
So there's a lot of other things you can draw.
你可以画风景 画篮子里的水果
You've got your landscapes. You've got your bowls of fruit.
画树木
Trees.
画谷仓 还有头顶水果的女人
A barn. The ladies with the fruit on the head.
我说过水果了
I said fruit.
可你没说头顶水果的女人
But you didn't say the ladies with the fruit on the head.
我是想让他不要再总想着女人
I'm trying to get him away from the ladies.
好 好的 好的
Ah, good. Good. Good.
这也太蠢了
This is so stupid.
万一我把汤洒她身上
What if I spill on her,
或者一不小心我的胸蹭到了她的手怎么办
or accidentally brush my boob against her hand?
我的意思是 她的手蹭到我的胸
I mean her hand against my boob.
哥们儿 放轻松 你能搞定的
Dude, stay cool. You got this.
我会一直在吧台
I'm gonna be at the bar the whole time.
你要是慌了 就过来找我
If you start to panic, just come get me.
小点声 她来了
Shh. There she is.
那是什么声音
What was that?
不知道 我以前也没听到过
I don't know. I've never heard it before.
别再那样了
Try not to let that happen again.
-你好卢克 -我挺好的
- Hi, Luke. - Pretty good.
我是说 你好萨梦
Uh, I mean, hi, Simone.
这是我爸
Uh, this is my dad.
爸 这是卢克
Dad, this is Luke.
你真有趣
You're funny.
长得有趣
Looking.
说得好
Clutch.
你还在这干嘛
What are you still doing here?
我是被什么搅昏了脑袋啊
What the hell got into me?
除了那酒保的舌头搅的吗
Besides the bartender's tongue?
是的 那确实有点不妥
Yes. Yes, well, that was a little inappropriate.
可我们别反应过激了
But let's not overreact.
在做重大人生决定前
It's perfectly natural to have a panic attack
惊慌失措是很正常的
before making a big life decision.
如果这是个错误的决定怎么办
What if it's the wrong decision?
如果托尼不是我的真命天子怎么办
What if Tony's not the guy?
如果他才是真命天子怎么办
What if he's the guy?
或是他 他好帅 他什么时候进来的
Or him? He is cute. When did he come in?
好了 你得集中注意力 萨尔
Okay, you need to focus, Sal.
你即将做出一个神圣的 终身的承诺
You are about to make a sacred, lifelong commitment.
你是在帮倒忙
You are not making this better!
天啊 是托尼
Oh, god, it's Tony.
我本该开车去接他参加婚礼的吗
I'm supposed to pick him up and drive him to the wedding?
所有人都给我闭嘴
Everybody shut up for a second!
好了 知道吗 我要嫁给他
Okay, you know what? I'm gonna marry him.
最差能怎样 大不了离婚
What's the worst that can happen? I get a divorce.
现在离婚的人多了去了
People do it all the time.
你快让我窒息了
oh, you're suffocating me!
现在改主意还不晚 你还没结呢
It is not too late. You are not married yet.
你说得对
You're right.
好 很好 尽情释放吧
Okay. That's good. Get it all out.
-到了 竖起来 - 妈
- Here. Stand up. - Okay, mom?
妈 妈 我的天啊 我能行
Mom. Mom. Oh, my god, mom, I think I got it.
我拖着这玩意儿到处跑都快十年了
I've been lugging this thing around for ten years.
好吧 你确定你不要我们留下来
Okay. Well, you sure you don't want us to stay
听你演奏吗
and--and hear you play?
没关系啦
Mm, that's okay.
我同意去吃晚餐
Yeah, I agreed to dinner,
可没同意来看"呆光乐队"演出
not tickets to the Electric Light Dorkestra.
别对你妹妹这么刻薄
Don't be so mean to your sister.
不是 那就是我们乐队的名字
No, that's our band's name.
你想回那个吃素食的店吗
So you wanna go back to that vegan place?
穿着皮夹克呢 会被恨死
Ooh. Leather jacket. Can't take the hate.
海莉
Haley!
加比 你在这干嘛呢
Gabby! What are you doing here?
就进来喝杯咖啡
I just stopped in for a bump of coffee
一会儿要去面条猫那里跟佐伊他们碰面
before I meet up with Zoe and those guys at Noodlecat.
-想一起来吗 -面条猫是什么
- Do you wanna go? - So what's--what's Noodlecat?
是个很酷的亚洲餐馆
Oh, it's this really cool Asian place
卖成千上百种不同的面条
that sells, like, a million different kinds of noodles.
但愿他们不卖猫
And hopefully, no cat.
-听起来很棒 -那你不介意我去吗
- Well, that sounds cool. - So you don't mind if I go?
我以为我们有安排了
Oh, I kind of thought we had plans.
是哦 没错
Oh. Yeah. You're right.
我完事了再去那里找你们
So I can meet you guys there after.
-你们要在那待多久 -不
- How long are you gonna be there? - No.
没关系 没关系 去吧
It's fine. It's fine. Go.
我在这看艾丽克斯演奏
I'll stay and watch Alex.
我好内疚
Oh, now I feel bad.
爱你
Love you!
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你是卢克的爸爸 对吧
You're Luke's dad, aren't you?
我是瓦莱丽 萨梦的妈妈
I'm Valerie, Simone's mom.
-我是菲尔 -你好
- Oh. Phil. - Hi.
我认得你
I recognized you
你主持了学校的才艺表演晚会
from when you hosted the school's talent night.
你身体柔韧性真好
You were incredibly limber.
归功于穿了合适的裤子
Ah, when you wear the right pants.
-请坐 -谢谢
- Please, sit down. - Thank you.
不客气
Yeah.
大约会进行得怎样了
So how is the big date going?
我不清楚
I don't know.
萨梦超紧张的
Simone was so nervous.
他们在网上聊的时候
When they were chatting on the computer,
我不得不帮她回复
I had to write everything for her.
真是有趣 我帮卢克做了同样的事
That's so funny. I did the same thing for Luke.
所以其实一直是我俩在聊天咯
So the whole time we were talking to each other?
等等 那这岂不是成了我们两个的约会
Wait, does that make this our date?
一位幽默又英俊的好父亲
Well, a good father, funny, handsome.
小女孩在网上可能遇到比这更差劲的呢
A girl could do a lot worse.
你知道吗 米奇尔
You know what, Mitchell?
抱歉我又要表现出我密苏里人的性格了
Forgive me if my Missouri is showing,
但她这不是结婚
but what she is doing is not marriage.
而是对婚姻的讥笑 她是在"讥婚"
It's a mockery of marriage. It's mockerage.
-我得阻止她 -别别 不行
- And I'm gonna stop it. - No, no, you're not.
我认为你在这事上掺入了一些
I can't help but think you're infusing the situation
你自己的郁闷沮丧情绪
with just a touch of your own frustration.
为什么 因为我们共同生活了十年吗
Why, because we've built a life together for the last ten years?
因为我们一起抚养孩子吗
Because we're raising a child?
还是因为我第一个想出在我们婚礼上
Or because I was the first person to think of doing
表演一段精心编排的舞蹈
an elaborately choreographed dance at our wedding,
而现在那点子都被人用烂了
and now it's been done to death?
如果能让你好受点的话
Makes you feel any better,
我想说我是死也不会同意跟你跳的
I was never gonna do that.
但我理解你
But... I get it.
你猜怎么着 只要伴郎
Well, you know what? She can't get married
不把婚戒递给她 她就没法结婚
if the best man doesn't hand over the wedding ring.
-你不会要这么做吧 -我会的
- You wouldn't. - Yes, I would.
婚戒在哪里 给我
Where is it? Give it to me.
-给我戒指 小卡 -别闹 别闹
- Give me the ring. Cam. - Stop. Stop.
-你得交给我 -我总算知道你们的体位了
- You have to give me... - Oh, well, this is a mystery solved.
谢谢
Thank you!
-好 我们开始吧 -好
- Okay. Let's go do this. - Okay.
托尼的帅气指数有几分
How hot does Tony look?
是跟酒保比还是...
On a scale of 1 to bartender, or...
别多嘴 小卡
Reel it in, Cam.
我觉得这东西坏掉了
I think this is broken.
我们得找个别的车位
We're gonna have to find another spot.
不行 看电影会迟到的
No, we'll be late for the movie.
你确定你的操作方法正确吗
Are you sure you're doing it right?
你我都知道 我懂得如何刷信用卡
We both know I know how to use a credit card.
好吧 我在收费器上留个条吧
All right, I'll put a note on the meter.
等我找张纸
Let me get a piece of paper.
也许这是个不祥的预兆
Maybe this is a bad sign.
也许我不该来看电影
Maybe I'm not supposed to be in the movie theater.
我应该在家照看孩子们
I'm supposed to be at home with my babies.
亲爱的 你我都知道 达丽娅懂得如何照看乔
Honey, we know that Daliya knows how to take care of Joe.
那曼尼呢 难道要他自己放洗澡水吗
And what about manny? He's supposed to run his own bath?
考虑到他最近的情况
You know, considering what's been going on with him,
也许你给他留点空间是好的
it might be good for you to give him a little space.
这本来就是他的主意
I mean, this was his idea.
什么是他的主意
What was?
让我们今晚出来约会
That we go out tonight,
好让我们能有些独处的时间
so that we could get some alone time.
真贴心
Oh, that's sweet.
-糟糕 -怎么了
- Uh-oh. - What?
我们得回家去 看 曼尼的笔记本
We gotta get home. Look--Manny's notebook.
又画画了还有首诗 《达丽娅颂》
More drawings and a poem-- "Ode to Daliya."
所以那不是我的胸部 是达丽娅的胸部吗
So those were not my boobs? They were Daliya's boobs?
对 这画的不是《下台阶的裸女》
Yep. This is not a "Nude descending a staircase,"
而是《扫台阶的裸女》
this is a "Nude vacuuming a staircase."
好了 曼尼 乔睡着了
Okay, Manny. Joe's asleep.
你晚餐想吃什么
What do you want for dinner?
实际上 晚餐已经准备好了
Actually, already taken care of.
食物不是用来摆弄的哦
You shouldn't play with your food.
你怎么会在这里
What are you doing here?
我知道你不高兴我离开
I knew you were upset I left,
我感觉很内疚 就回来了
and I felt bad, so I came back,
你因为内疚而回来的吗
You're here out of guilt?
我知道 我长大了
I know. I'm growing up.
你干吗对我翻白眼
Why are you rolling your eyes at me?
我这样做多贴心啊
I'm doing a nice thing.
因为我希望你是因为你想回来才回来的
Because I want you to be here because you wantto be here.
好吧 你现在真的好黏人
Okay, you're being really needy right now.
天呐 你更年期到了吗
Oh, my god. Are you going through the change?
不要每次我表现出点情绪就这么问
Stop asking me that every time I express an emotion.
不 我没有 只是因为这里太热了
And no, I am not. It's just so damn hot in here.
我很失望 仅此而已
I am disappointed, that's all.
你小的时候 我们做什么都在一起
When you were little, we used to do everything together.
而我以为那时的你又回归了
And I thought maybe you were coming back around,
我们又能成为闺蜜了
and we could be friends again.
我只是怀念作为女儿生活的一部分的感觉了
I just... miss being part of my daughter's life.
大家好 感谢各位的到来
Hey, everybody. Thanks for coming.
我还以为是要演奏古典音乐的呢
I thought this was supposed to be some sort of classical thing.
我也是
Me, too.
她还会唱歌
She sings?
我都认不出那个小妮子了
I don't even know who that is.
天呐 菲尔 你好幽默
Oh, my god, Phil, you are hilarious.
是的 那是我20年来深得老婆欢心的诀窍
Yep. That's how I got my wife of 20 years.
麻烦结账 谢谢
Could we get the check, please?
我来吧
Oh, I got this.
幽默又大方
Ooh, funny and generous.
要是我丈夫能像你一样
If my husband were more like you...
也许我就不会离婚了
maybe I'd still be married.
要是我老婆在这里
Well, if my wife were here,
她会希望我清楚我要对她绝对忠诚
she'd want me to be clear that I'm fully committed to her.
你知道的 对吧
You know that, right?
什么
What?
没有 我只是想确定一下
No, I just wanna make sure,
因为你解开了一颗扣子
because you unbuttoned a button,
而我...爱我的老婆 所以
and I... love my wife, so--
是你跟我打情骂俏
You were the one who was flirting
-还说我们是在约会 -那是个玩笑
- and saying we're on a date. - That was a joke,
但要是我误导了你 我很抱歉
But I'm--I'm sorry if I misled you at all.
谢谢
Thank you.
但你还摸了人家呢
But there was a lot of touching.
我碰了一下你的肩膀而已
I touched your shoulder for a second.
不 更像是轻抚 像这样
No, it was more of a stroke, like this--
好吧 非常抱歉
Okay. I'm so sorry
我用胸部碰了你的手
for touching your hand with my boob.
我是说用你的手碰了我的胸部
I mean my boob with your hand.
你很喜欢玩这种把戏吗
Is this your little game?
你故意勾搭一个失落的离异女人
You cop a feel on a sad divorcee
然后假装是我在调戏你
and then pretend I'm the one coming on to you?
-这样感觉如何 -好奇怪
- How does that feel? - Oh. Weird.
你喜欢吗 是不是
You like it? Yeah?
这样又如何
Little bit of that?
-爽吧 -什么 不要
- Yeah. - Little bit of whoa. No.
你喜欢这样 是不是
You probably like this. Don't you?
打住 你女儿就在那边呢
Oh, stop it. Your daughter's right over there.
我的小货车就停在外边
My minivan is right outside.
我不是那个意思
That is not what I meant.
比萨饼真好吃
This pizza is delicious.
我也爱吃 我们的共同点真多
I like it, too. We have so much in common.
你看过菜单的背面了吗
Have you seen the back of your menu?
丝绸一般的长发 细腻的橄榄色皮肤
"With silken hair and supple olive skin
还有那双会洗衣服的纤纤玉手
and hands that wash the laundry of my kin..."
曼尼
Oh, Manny...
下面还有12行呢
You still have 12 lines to go.
剧透一下 我爱你
Spoiler alert-- I love you.
好了 离保姆远一点
Okay, back away from the nanny.
我的天 完全就像麦当娜的MTV一样淫靡嘛
Oh, my god, it looks like a Madonna video in here!
-你们怎么没去看电影 -我们现在就得谈谈
- Why aren't you at the movies? - We need to talk right now.
-你对我儿子做了什么 -我没有
- What have you done to my son?! - I didn't--
她什么也没做
She didn't do anything.
你们为什么非要让我丢人
Why do you have to embarrass me?
让你丢人 如果你没有爱上...
Embarrass you? Maybe if you didn't fall in love...
别吵了
Stop this!
你们会吵醒宝宝的
You're going to wake the baby.
我要和曼尼私下说两句
Now Manny and I are having a private discussion.
请给我们一点时间
So please, give us a minute.
-我现在就给你时间 -歌洛莉亚 歌洛莉亚
- I'll give you your minute right this minute. - Gloria. Gloria.
说吧 曼尼
Go ahead, Manny.
我不是说我们现在就要做什么
I'm not saying we need to do anything right away.
我只是要求你等我几年
I'm just asking you to wait a few years.
你真好
You are so sweet.
无论谁最终和你在一起
Whoever ends up with you
她都将是全世界最幸运的女生
is the luckiest woman in the world.
那人可以是你啊
That could be you.
不
No.
我不够幸运 因为我出生太早了
I am unlucky, because I was born too soon.
我不能让你这样虚度年华
And I can't have you wait around.
诗人要成长
Poets have to live.
而且过几年 你对我的感觉就会不同了
Besides, in a few years, you'll feel differently.
你错了 我这辈子对你的感觉都不会变
You're wrong. I'll feel this way for the rest of my life.
曼尼 等等
Well, Manny, wait.
-曼尼宝贝 -别来烦我
- Ay, Manny, papito lindo-- - Leave me alone.
对不起
Sorry about that.
不用 这是我收到的最甜蜜的礼物
Don't be. It's the sweetest offer I've ever gotten.
真对不起 我刚才冲你大叫
I am so sorry that I screamed at you.
你刚才对他说的话真贴心
It was so nice what you told him in there.
我照顾曼尼 你照顾宝宝
I take Manny, you take the little one?
好的
Okay.
-你可能只需要 -她知道怎么做 杰
- You probably just-- - She knows what to do, Jay.
提拉米苏
Tiramisu.
我超爱吃他的提拉米苏
I love his tiramisu.
婚姻是一种承诺
Marriage is a promise.
是向全世界宣布你们对彼此的
It says to the world that you share a love
爱与承诺
and a commitment to each other
随着时间推移 那种爱只会越来越深
That will only grow deeper as the years go by.
你们有写誓词吗
Now have you two written vows?
是的 我先来
Yeah, I'll go.
婚姻让我很害怕
Marriage terrifies me.
你看米奇和小卡
Take Mitch and Cam.
我以前总是觉得他们的人生闷死了
I used to think their life looked so boring.
我永远做不来 付账单 洗盘子
I could never do it. Pay bills? Wash dishes?
每天醒来都看到同一张脸
Wake up to the same face every day?
我为他们感到悲哀
I felt sorry for them.
你想表达什么意思
Where is this headed?
但他们不闷
But they're not bored.
原来 只要是和真命天子在一起
It turns out when you're with the right person,
就可以穿着睡衣在晚上十点换壁架纸
you can change shelf paper at 10:00 at night in your pajamas
哪里都不想去
and not wanna be anywhere else.
他们对彼此的爱就有这么深
That's how much they love each other.
-太对了 -刚才我看到你的脸
- We sure do. - And when I just saw your face,
让我想起
I remembered...
我也是这样的爱你
that's how much I love you.
多谢你出现在我生命里
Thanks for being here.
我们哪里也不会去 萨尔
We wouldn't be anywhere else, Sal.
你有准备誓词吗
And do you have anything prepared?
说吧 宝贝
Hit me, baby.
昨晚我和脱衣舞娘舌吻了
I made out with a stripper last night.
抱歉 我只是想在婚前坦白
Sorry. I just wanna start this clean.
我和酒保舌吻了 就在一小时前
I made out with a bartender... an hour ago.
你这样说 不是为了想安慰我吧
You're not just saying that to make me feel better, are you?
帮我作证 我有没有
Back me up. Didn't I?
-她绝对舌吻了 -我吻了
- She totally did. - I totally did!
-他长得好帅 -那人非常帅气
- Yeah. He was hot, too. - He was very good-looking.
-太好了 -真特别的誓词
- Nice. - Well. That was different.
-戒指在谁手上 -我这儿
- Who's got the ring? - I do.
给我
Hand 'em over.
非常感谢
Thank you guys so much.
艾丽克斯 宝贝 太棒了
Alex, honey, amazing.
你为什么没有告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us?
-我不知道 -刚刚真是太棒了
- Oh, I-I don't know. - That was so good.
如果我不认识你
If I didn't know you,
我肯定会说 那妹子酷毙了
I'd be all like, "That chick is cool."
各位好 我是艾丽克斯的妈妈
Hey, guys, hi. I'm Alex's mom.
你们太优秀了
You were terrific.
你们好 我是她姐姐
Hey, and I'm her sister.
我们要去吃晚餐
We're gonna go get some dinner.
你要一起来吗
Do you wanna come with us?
你可以带乐队的朋友一起来
You can bring your friends from the band.
不用了 多谢 我们要出去
Um, no, thanks. We're actually going out,
会有人送我回家的 回头见
and I have a ride home, so see you guys later.
好的
Okay.
我的天 真是不好意思
Oh, my god. Sorry about that.
她刚刚是为我们两个道歉吗
Did she just apologize for us?
-正是 -但我们只是想示好
- Yep. - But we were just being nice.
感觉差劲吧
Sucks, doesn't it?
卢克 抱歉萨梦的妈妈那么早就把她拉走了
Luke, I'm sorry Simone's mom dragged her away so fast.
没事 反正我也快没话说了
It's okay. I was running out of things to say.
看来我把你的好事搞砸了
Guess I kind of blew it for you, didn't I?
没有 现在她妈禁止她和我出去
No. Now that her mom doesn't want her going out with me anymore,
萨梦更想和我在一起了
Simone wants me more than ever.
我想她快到反叛时期了
I guess she's heading into a rebellious stage.
追求女孩的最佳时期
Best time to get 'em.
永远不要害怕追求自己配不上的女孩
Never be afraid to go after a girl who's out of your league.
我就是例子 这样才追到你妈
I did. That's how I got your mom.
是啊 我总是好奇你怎么会追到老妈的
Yeah, I always wondered how you pulled that one off.
她当时也处在反叛时期
She was in a rebellious stage, too.
没错 你外公当年可不像现在这样喜欢我啊
Yep, grandpa wasn't always as crazy about me as he is now.
我去开香槟 拿酒杯
I'm gonna go pop the champagne and get some glasses.
我来帮忙
I'll help.
我去拿益智桌游
I'm gonna get Cranium.
抱歉你不能参加婚礼
Sorry you couldn't come to the wedding.
只限成人参加
It was no kids.
没关系 我参加你下一场婚礼就好了
It's okay. I'll go to your next one.
她的意思是
She--she just means when
等她长大以后
she's not a kid anymore, you know?
她知道我的意思
She knows what I mean.
我不喜欢你
I don't like you.
我才不在乎呢
I'll get over it.